<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on Tech Portfolio - Marcus Jacobson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/techblog/categories/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on Tech Portfolio - Marcus Jacobson</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/techblog/categories/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hugo - Add taxonomy to sort blog posts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techblog/posts/hugo-add-taxonomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techblog/posts/hugo-add-taxonomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-need-to-sort-blog-posts&#34;&gt;The need to sort blog posts&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I have been adding more blog posts, I realized that I needed to start sorting them by category, to make finding relevant articles in the future easier. Fortunately, with a little research, the answer to this was pretty straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;add-a-taxonomy-section-to-hugotoml&#34;&gt;Add a taxonomy section to hugo.toml&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Within the &lt;strong&gt;hugo.toml&lt;/strong&gt; file, I added the following section after &lt;strong&gt;[&amp;ldquo;params&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[taxonomies]&#xD;&#xA;  category = &amp;#34;categories&amp;#34;&#xD;&#xA;  tag = &amp;#34;tags&amp;#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This gives me the option to do both categorization and add tags in the future. For now I just added categories, since I don&amp;rsquo;t have a search functionality on my side. If I add search later though, having the option to implement tags will be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hugo - Creating the Profile page</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techblog/posts/hugo-profile-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techblog/posts/hugo-profile-page/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;customizing-a-profile-page-within-the-hugo-site&#34;&gt;Customizing a profile page within the hugo site.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of weeks since I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on the Hugo site. However, I came back to it today to work on building out the Portfolio page that I created as a placeholder in the past, to get this site closer to something I&amp;rsquo;d be more comfortable sharing with the world. I started by filling out details within the placeholder markdown file I created before. Here were my goals:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hugo - Fix home page indentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techblog/posts/fix-home-page-indent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techblog/posts/fix-home-page-indent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-issue&#34;&gt;The issue&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As part of the Ananke theme for Hugo, the home page by default displays the most current blog posts. This is what I was looking for, and the main reason I chose this theme for the ss. As with the main page for any section, the home page uses a &lt;strong&gt;_index.md&lt;/strong&gt; page in the root of the &lt;strong&gt;content&lt;/strong&gt; folder, which is empty by default other than the headers. This is because the main purpose for this theme is to be used as a blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hugo - Fixing broken image links</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techblog/posts/hugo-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techblog/posts/hugo-images/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-hugo-images-were-broken&#34;&gt;My Hugo images were broken!&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quick update for today, with another Hugo tip. As I have worked with markdown before, specifically while managing Wikis in Azure DevOps and GitHub, I simply created a subdirectory within my repository in the same area as the markdown files for my articles, and then pointed to my image files using the typical syntax of &lt;code&gt;![alt text](imagelink)&lt;/code&gt;. When building my site within Hugo, it even properly ported these image files into the &lt;strong&gt;public&lt;/strong&gt; site files, however no matter what I did, my links were broken.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hugo - Customize the Ananke Theme</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techblog/posts/customize-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techblog/posts/customize-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;continuing-the-hugo-journey&#34;&gt;Continuing the Hugo Journey&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As discussed in the previous Blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ve started to host my own tech blog site using the Hugo platform and hosting through GitHub pages. Today I decided to play with the platform a little more and see if I could extend my site to multiple pages and make it more of a personal homepage along with the blog. With this goal in mind, I worked on the following items:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Blog Post - Creating this Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techblog/posts/deploy-hugo-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techblog/posts/deploy-hugo-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-i-created-this-blog&#34;&gt;Why I created this blog&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My name is Marcus, and I am an IT professional focused in Azure Cloud Deployments, and working to improve my skills in the Security and AI spaces. This blog is meant to be a space for me to focus on the following subjects:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Discussions on personal projects I am working on&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Details on deployments with screenshots and code snippets, to help others as they come across the content&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Posts relating to learning activities I am working on, including certifications.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog is posted using the Hugo framework within GitHub pages. I chose this method since it is a free way to host content and it allows me to still have the control around content publishing and site theming. For more details on using Hugo, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;https://gohugo.io/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
